<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Grazfather</title>
    <link>https://grazfather.github.io/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Grazfather</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grazfather.github.io/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - November-December 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2017-08-15-reading-nov-dec-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2017-08-15-reading-nov-dec-2016/</guid>
      <description>Game Hacking - I was really excited by this book, since game hacking is a big part of how I got into reverse engineering. I even pre-ordered it and submitted a bunch of corrections in the pre-release (Some of which was not corrected, which is interesting&amp;hellip;). Overall this book was disappointing, and I think my high hopes were based on the publisher. I was hoping for a book similar to Practical Malware Analysis, with high quality exercises, and matching writeups of every single exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - September-October 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2017-01-22-reading-sept-oct-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2017-01-22-reading-sept-oct-2016/</guid>
      <description>The Return of the King - While I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy this one quite as much as I did The Two Towers, I still enjoyed it a lot. Yet again I was surprised by how much Peter Jackson left out of the films. Of note, the books goes on for a good handful of pages beyond where Sam and Frodo reunite with the rest of the fellowship: They return to The Shire to find that a lot has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Malware Analysis Labs</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-09-11-practical-malware-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-09-11-practical-malware-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I owe Practical Malware Analysis for kickstarting my career in security. Before reading it (and getting into CTFs) I was working as an embedded systems developer, and then a developer at a bug bounty company.
PMA has got to be the best technical book I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. On the OpenToAll slack it&amp;rsquo;s the book I&amp;rsquo;m mostly likely to recommend, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I am doing here. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked through every lab in the book, currently available on my github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - June-August 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-09-01-reading-june-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-09-01-reading-june-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>Wool Omnibus (Audiobook) - I picked this up because it was something like $3. I had already read the original Wool a few times and enjoyed it, and I enjoyed this one as much. This book takes place in an underground silo where a group of people has lived for generations. Their only view to the outside world is through a camera that points to the bleak post-apocalyptic world outside. The dust builds up on the lens, however, so it must be cleaned (with wool pads, where the book gets its name), so they send out their criminals (which is a death sentence).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - April-May 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-06-01-reading-april-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-06-01-reading-april-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>The Willpower Instinct - I enjoyed this book a lot. I head of it while reviewing The Power of Habit, a book I read a few months ago (and didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly love). This book does it a lot better. More interesting, relevant facts (with citations), more actionable items, more engaging. While I felt that The Power of Habit was there to break habits (such as smoking or overeating), this book was better geared for picking up and keeping positive habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - February-March 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-04-01-reading-february-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-04-01-reading-february-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Mastery: Robert Greene (Author of &amp;ldquo;48 Laws of Power&amp;rdquo;) uses examples of historical &amp;lsquo;masters&amp;rsquo; of their domain, such as Mozart, and well as more contemporary masters, such at Paul Graham. Apparently a lot of practice will make you good at something. Really though, I enjoyed this book a lot. Each chapter begins with a story from one of the masters, which focuses on a specific task that the author deems important in the quest for mastery, he then breaks down how the master succeeded in this and how it paid off, and then ends with a more direct summary of how you should apply it to your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - January 2016</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-02-01-reading-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-02-01-reading-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Game Plan for Life: The Power of Mentoring - This book was a recommendation from my brother, and I was hesitant to read it just because I had a huge book queue, and I don&amp;rsquo;t care about basketball. I was bored, though, on my flight home from Christmas vacation, so I cracked it open, and I am glad it did. John Wooden, the legendary UCLA basketkall coach, starts off talking about seven people whom he believes were important mentors in his life including some people whom he&amp;rsquo;s never met (like Abraham Lincoln).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reading Summary - 2015</title>
      <link>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-01-01-reading-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grazfather.github.io/posts/2016-01-01-reading-2015/</guid>
      <description>I intend to do these more frequently, but here’s a dump of the books I read last year.
The Dinner - I don&amp;rsquo;t often read fiction, and I kind of wish I hadn&amp;rsquo;t wasted my time with this one. There&amp;rsquo;s a subtle twist that&amp;rsquo;s delivered pretty well, but over all I just don&amp;rsquo;t think it was interesting enough to make it worth a 300 page book.
Gray Hat Python - The examples are a lot of fun and the author does a pretty good job explaining how everything works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>